(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T08:23:28.733049",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live. ぱるすにゃりちゃぺくど
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live: Parusunyarichapekudo
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To all attendees
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live. パンパカパーティー
[Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live -Panpaka Party-]
Sponsor 協賛
[Sponsors]
心からで
From the bottom of our hearts...
こっちこっちこっち！
Over here, over here!
今日二人じゃないっすね？
It's not just two of us today, huh?
え？
Huh?
二人？
Two of them?
さっきの ここでやった人たち
The people who were performing right here earlier.
え？
Huh?
心からで
From the bottom of our hearts...
ジョイしとこうぜ！
Let's Joy it up!
JOYSOUND X1
本日は、猫又おかゆ セカンドライブ ペルソニャリスペクトにご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Nekomata Okayu's 2nd live, "Personalispect," today!
めっちゃ盛り上がってくれてるじゃん。
You guys are getting so hyped up!
え、みんな、1＋1は？
Hey everyone, what's 1 + 1?
いいね、今日ラグないね。
Nice, no lag today.
はい、もぐもぐおかゆです。こんばんはー！
Yep, it's Mogu Mogu Okayu. Good evening!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To make sure you enjoy the live to the very end, I have a few announcements for you.
いい返事。公園中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Good response. Photography, audio, and video recording during the performance are strictly prohibited.
場内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮ください。
Smoking is prohibited inside the venue. Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
In the unlikely event you feel unwell, please do not push yourself and notify nearby staff.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ステージに物を投げ込むなど、他のみんなに迷惑になったり、公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
Mosh pits, crowdsurfing, throwing objects on stage, and other disruptions are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってくださいね！
Please follow the rules and have fun!
イエーイ！
Yeah!
また、本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に 入り、客席が映り込む場合があります。
Also, cameras for video streaming and photography will be in the venue, and seats may be captured.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーション等に使用される可能性がありますので、あらかじめご承知ください。
Please be aware that these videos and photos may be used for promotional purposes.
ここまでの影ナレ、実はフリガナをね、つけてもらったので、スラスラ読めてるでしょ？
The shadow narration up until now... actually, they put furigana for me, so I'm reading it smoothly, right?
ありがとうございます。またライブのハッシュタグは「#おかゆセカンド」です。
Thank you. Also, the hashtag for the live is #OkayuSecond.
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてくれると嬉しいな！
I'd be so happy if you use the hashtag to hype things up!
それでは開演までもう少しです。
Well then, we're just a little bit away from the start.
街にまた声出しありのセカンドライブ、おにぎりゃーの声を聞かせてね！
For our second live with cheering allowed, let me hear your voices, Onigirya!
イエーイ！
Yeah!
全然いらないじゃんか
It's totally unnecessary, isn't it?
わかってくれないじゃんか
You don't understand, do you?
まあ、仕方ないなんて思いはしないけど
Well, I can't help it, or so I don't think.
全然笑えないじゃんか
You can't even smile at all, can you?
面白くなりもしないじゃんか
You're not even having any fun, are you?
あぁ、こんなもんなかって期待は以下略
Ah, if that's all it is, expectations are below zero.
はぁ、そもそものはなし君のこととか求めていることとかわからないやん
Huh? In the first place, I don't get your feelings or what you're asking for.
どろどろになるまで煮込んだ感情やけどしちゃうくらいあっちあっち
Emotions boiled down until they're a mushy mess, enough to make me feel sick.
笑顔に甘えてるんじゃないの？優しさにとかされてんじゃないの？
Are you just giving in to your smile? Are you just taken by the kindness?
答えがほしいわけじゃなくてたまに思うだけ気にしないで
It's not that I want an answer, I just think about it sometimes, so don't worry about it.
まあ、そういうこと
Well, something like that.
あかんべーで忘れましょう、後悔はいらないのよ
Let's forget it with a "Nyah-ner-nyah-ner," regrets aren't needed!
いいよいいよおし殺してあげちゃうわ
That's right, that's right, I'll go ahead and kill you with kindness!
あかんべーで忘れたらめいっぱいドキドキしよう？
If you forget it with a "Nyah-ner-nyah-ner," let's make your heart race endlessly!
いいよいいもっと良い子になれたらあげましょう
That's right, that's right, once you can be an even better child, I'll give it to you.
しりもしないくせにわかったふりそれでも好きだなんて面白いや
Even though you don't even know, you act like you do, and yet you say you like it—how funny.
あきらめの鼓動裏で鳴るハロー混ざり合うハートは狂気狂気
Beating behind the heartbeat of giving up, a hello mixed with madness, madness.
どこまでを許せばいいのかってぐるぐる回る妄想は勝手
How far is it okay to forgive? Round and round go selfish fantasies.
頭の中をタブーループ僕が思うのはどっちどっち
Inside my head is a tabu group, what I think is tochi-tochi.
せんぎれたぼくくって大満足？腹が満たせりゃってそりゃそうだろ
Is a polished skull total satisfaction? It's only natural that it fills your stomach.
ここに名案ありますよお口拭いとくおかわりはどうだい
There's a good name for it here, I'll keep my mouth shut, how about seconds?
あかんべーの続きとか思ったってやりたやらないのよだってだって虚しくなるだけだから
Did you think it was a continuation of "Nyah-ner-nyah-ner"? No, that's just making it hollow.
あかんべーを忘れたらめいっぱい笑顔になれるだってだってそうさ僕は
If you forget "Nyah-ner-nyah-ner," you can have a full smile.
あかんべーで忘れましょう、後悔はいらないのよ
Let's forget it with a "Nyah-ner-nyah-ner," regrets aren't needed!
いいよいいよおし殺してあげちゃうわ
That's right, that's right, I'll go ahead and kill you with kindness!
あかんべーで忘れたらめいっぱいドキドキしよう？
If you forget it with a "Nyah-ner-nyah-ner," let's make your heart race endlessly!
いいよいいもっと良い子になれたらあげましょう
That's right, that's right, once you can be an even better child, I'll give it to you.
ねぇねぇびっくりしちゃった？もしかして怖くなっちゃった？
Hey, hey, were you surprised? Could it be that you got scared?
そう全部なんちゃって驚かせてごめんね
So that was all a lie, sorry for startling you.
ねぇねぇびっくりしちゃった？もしかして怖くなっちゃった？
Hey, hey, were you surprised? Could it be that you got scared?
そう全部なんちゃってどちらが僕でしょうか
So that was all a lie, which one am I?
僕の暗い暗い暗くてで君は言葉を待っていたんだ
Well, in this deep, deep, darkness, you were waiting for words, weren't you?
倒れないように伸ばした願いに応えていくだけだよ
It's just that I reached out a hand, like a prayer that wouldn't break.
あたえることしかできないよ好きだから見えた空
I can't even give you that this year.
ほら 夜のよに ぼくの色じゃなくても
Even if it's not my color,
素敵に素敵に着こなせるよ
I'll make it look wonderful.
きみの視界のぼくは何の色に見えますか
What color will I look like...
in your field of vision?
ハリめぐらしたセンサーで
With a sensor that wanders around,
ゆうもなくすきなだあすなみだをおとすから
I'll deliver my tears to you, naturally.
いっしょうまといますぐまっていてくれ
So please wait for me forever.
かぜをひくまでふれたかおにふれることができたらいいのにな
I wish I could touch your smiling face until the wind stops.
あたしのいろはだれかのことばうけとるために
To receive someone else's words,
はなをさかせるの
I let flowers bloom.
なみだかれたらむげんきゅうえん
If my tears dry up, it's infinity.
ぼくはめをひらいてくちをあけいきをしないでもいろをのむ
I open my eyes, open my mouth,
and swallow the color without breathing.
きみはぼくからなにがみえる？とそうぞうするこころがほしかった
What can you see in me? That's what my imagining heart wanted.
こえをからすことのないようにぼくにしっといろづいたしでね
So that there's no misunderstanding, paint me in your colors forever.
きみの視界のぼくはどんな色に塗りますか
What color will I look like...
in your world?
きせつにさらわれるまではゆうもなくでを
Until I'm swept away by the seasons, I'll naturally...
なみだをしりたいからいっしょうまとおうごかんおくればそばにいるほどうつるぼくでかざることができたらいいのにな
want to know your tears, wear my clothes, and send my five senses.
しめっぽいきせつのデコレーションさかせるためのぞうかんかんけいのこして おいた余白で
Leaving the negative space of a humid seasonal decoration,
きみのかんかくをうらうう
I want to savor your senses.
なまのほねはえぐいから
Raw bones are gruesome,
ちゃんとひをとおしてたべてね
so make sure you cook them through.
うさびすはづるいかな
Service is gross, isn't it?
それもいしんでしんのれしぴ みんなじぶんいつわってるかい
Let's all try out this innovative recipe.
うそのばんこくはくらんかい みんなじぶんいつわってるかい かいいたみをかいならして
Panting with lies, fake universality, pretending to be someone else,
かいいたみをかいならして
and nursing your pain.
さあきらいだけどすき もつくってもおいしい
Come on, I hate it, but I love it.
ぎぐるみをきてはくしてあげる まかせないように おこらせないように
Even if I make it, it's delicious. I'll put on a stuffed animal costume and clap for you.
ちょうどよくきみとあそびたいのだ
Just right, because I want to play with you.
ねこかぶりのねこかぶりの ちょっとおくびょうなきみがあすき
Cat, covering, cat, covering,
a slightly timid you is what I like.
ねこかぶりのねこかぶりの とりづくろってるぼくがすき
Cat, covering, cat, covering,
よそおいしってるきみがすきだよ
I like the pretender that I am, because you knew my true self.
おもうとうとではおちがい たてまえもようやくよりしょだい
Thoughts and actions are different. Pretending and reality are also a matter of degree.
みんなじぶんいつわってるかい
Everyone, are you deceiving yourselves?
ひとりぼっちの音楽隊
Are you living alone?
みんなじぶんたってるかい くびわのすずならして
Everyone, are you standing alone?
くびわのすずならして
Ring your collar's bell.
むずかしいなんだかハッピー しんどくてもへいき
It's hard, it's difficult, but I'm fine.
あめぼめなゆめをみせてあげる
I'll show you a dizzy dream.
きづつけないように おいづめないように
So I don't hurt you or corner you,
よあけまできみとふざけあうのだ
until dawn, I want to mess around with you.
ねこかぶりのねこかぶりの つめをまるめてるきみがすき
Cat, covering, cat, covering,
the you with curled claws is what I like.
ねこかぶりのねこかぶりの なみだをみせないぼくがすき
Cat, covering, cat, covering,
いたみを知ってるきみがすきだよ
I like the me who doesn't show tears, because you know my pain.
もうもうごうかいゆう みんなきょうはきてくれてありがとう
Oh, go, go, go, go, You, everyone, thank you for coming today!
ここからのね きみはねこねこ ぼくらのねこのぶんは
From here on, you are cat, cat, the cat part of "Cat, Covering,"
みんなにもいっしょにうたってほしいなと思って
I want everyone to sing along with me, okay?
いい？ きふはねこねこっておおきこでうたうんだよ
The keyphrase is "Cat, Covering," sung in a loud voice, okay?
いくよ せーの！
Here we go! Ready, go!
君はネコ ネコ ファスナー付きのネコ
You're a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper
君はヒト ヒト ファスナー付きのヒト
You're a human, a human, a human with a zipper
あれはUFO UFO ファスナー付きのUFO
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper
君はネコ ネコ ファスナー付きのネコ
You're a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper
君はヒト ヒト ファスナー付きのヒト
You're a human, a human, a human with a zipper
あれはUFO UFO ファスナー付きのUFO
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper
君はネコ ネコ ファスナー付きのネコ
You're a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper
君はヒト ヒト ファスナー付きのヒト
You're a human, a human, a human with a zipper
あれはUFO UFO ファスナー付きのUFO
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper
君は誰？ 誰？ 特別な人
Who are you? Who? A special person
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko kaburiina, neko kaburiina
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you, a little cowardly
君も僕も馴染めない世界で
In a world where neither of us fits in,
やっと見つけた居場所だから
It's a place we finally found.
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko kaburiina, neko kaburiina
取り繕ってる僕が好き？
Do you like the me who puts up a front?
弱さを知ってる君が好きだよ
I love that you know my weaknesses.
君も僕も誤魔化してる世界で
In a world where both of us are bluffing,
明日もまた会えたらいいの
I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko kaburiina, neko kaburiina
良さを知ってる君が好きだよ
I love that you know my good sides.
3回目の
The third time's
もぐもぐ！
Mogumogu!
いや、もうさ、励みも含めて
Man, including the encouragement,
3回ももぐもぐおかゆって言っちゃったよ。
I went and said mogumogu okayu three times!
このね、ライブの空気感でみんなが僕が変なこと言っても「えーい！」って言ってくれるからね。
In this live concert atmosphere, even if I say something weird, you all go 'Yay!'
これですよ。ということでね、やっとこの日が来ました。横浜！
This is it. So, this day has finally come. Yokohama!
飛び交って おります。いや、もうさ、あっという間すぎたんだよ、この時間まで。
flying around. Man, this time went by way too fast until now.
さっきまで僕ね、お弁当食べてたんだけど、え？食べれるでしょ、お弁当！
Just a minute ago, I was eating a bento. Huh? Of course you can eat a bento!
僕の食べたお弁当は、何お弁当でしょうか？
What kind of bento do you think I ate?
怒っててよくわかんないけど。え、ちなみにさ、
I don't really get what I'm saying, but... by the way,
おにぎりだよって人手挙げて！
Raise your hand if you thought 'Onigiri!'
最高最高！見えてるよ、ありがとね！
Awesome, awesome! I can see you, thank you!
ヤッホー！
Yahoo!
もちろんね、アリーナ席の配信チケット見てるみんなも見えてるからね！
Of course, I can see everyone watching the arena seat streaming tickets too!
ということでですね、皆さんなんとお気づきだと思いますが、本日のバンドは生演奏となっております！
So, as you probably all noticed, today's band features live music!
すごーい！
So cool!
やっぱね、生演奏
Live music really
おなかにくるよね、おなかに。
hits you right in the gut, doesn't it?
うおー、くる！おなかにくるぞ！
Whoa, it hits! It hits right in the gut!
僕のさっき食べたお弁当も
The bento I ate earlier
多分ぐってなってんだろ、きっとな。
is probably all churned up inside now.
えー、あとですね、残念なお知らせがございます。
Um, also, I have some unfortunate news.
これ定番だよね、もう一回やりたい、もう一回やりたい！
This is a classic, right? I wanna do it again, I wanna do it again!
ここで、残念なお知らせがあります！
Here is some unfortunate news!
なんと、本編無料チラ見せはここで終了です！
Our free main stream preview ends right here!
ごめんね。概要欄とかあとYouTubeのチラ見せにはさ、固定してるコメントのところからチケット買えるので是非お願いします！
Sorry. You can buy tickets from the pinned comment in the description and YouTube preview, so please check it out!
後悔はね、させません、約束いたしますので。
I promise you won't regret it.
はい、配信で楽しんでる人はハッシュタグ #おかゆセカンド でいっぱい呟いてくれると嬉しいです！ありがとう！
And to everyone enjoying the stream, I'd be happy if you tweet a lot with #OkayuSecond! Thank you!
あとね、みんなさポチポチポチポチペンライト変えてくれてたじゃん。
Also, you guys were all clicking and changing your penlights, right?
実は、この僕の
Actually, this mic of mine...
あ、話すと聞こえなくなるわ。
Ah, if I talk, you can't hear me.
このマイクの色が実はね、ペンライトの色になってるから、何色にするかかんないときはこのペンライトの...
The color of this mic actually matches the penlight color, so when you don't know what color to use, match this penlight...
色、参考にしてみてください。
Please use this color as a reference.
いぇーい！
Yay!
ま、遠くって見えづらい人は、あんまりね、大きな声じゃ言えないですけど、とりあえず紫色にしとけば間違いなくて
Well, for those far away who might find it hard to see—I shouldn't say this too loudly, but if you just make it purple, you can't go wrong.
間違いありません、本当に！
There's no mistake, truly!
ということで、今日はいろんな表情の僕を楽しんでいってください！
With that said, please enjoy all kinds of expressions of me today!
いぇーい！
Yay!
では、次の曲いきましょう！
Now then, let's go to the next song!
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live "ペルソニャ・リスペクト"
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live "PERSONYA RESPECT"
平凡で いいかなって
Would being ordinary be fine?
それだけで 私
Is just that, being me...
いいの？
Is it okay?